Okay, so let's discuss the PIMBock Guide
processes when it comes to procurement
management and again this as it relates to
PIMBock Guide version 6.
So in PIMBock 6, there are three processes
in procurement, as you can see,
and they span planning, executing and the
monitoring controlling process groups.
So under planning, right, the first one is
plan procurement management.
And just like any of those knowledge
areas, right, the very first process is
always plan something management, right,
something meaning the knowledge area.
So in this case, the knowledge area is
procurement management.
So plan procurement management.
And so the output of plan procurement
procurement management plan.
So the artifact that we are creating,
right, the document that we're creating is
the procurement management plan,
otherwise known as the output,
right, in PIMBOC version six, up to PIMBOC
version six, they were known as outputs.
So the output then the plan
procurement management
management plan is the
procurement management plan.
Remember, any management plan is
documenting procedures, documenting the how.
So the procurement management
plan then is documenting how
we're going to basically manage
and control our procurement.
How we're going to plan, execute,
monitor our control.
monitor and control our procurement.
And so the procurement management plan is
talked about in detail.
in a separate video.
And executing, you have the process called
Conduct Procurement.
And Conduct Procurement refers to,
once we have planned our procurement,
then we're going to reach out to vendors.
So conduct procurement means, or it refers
to reaching out to vendors, discussing the
project with the vendor, or the vendors,
getting our proposals back from these
vendors, selecting one of those vendors,
and then finally signing the contract.
with one of those vendors.
So everything up until
signing the contract or the
agreement is referred to
as conduct procurement.
Planned procurement refers to we are
planning.
Are we going to outsource the work?
Are we going to do it in-house?
And then plus what potential vendors can
we be reaching out to?
With conduct procurement, it actually
physically refers to reaching out to
vendors, interacting
with them, talking to them,
and everything up until
signing the contract.
Once we have signed the
contract with the vendor,
now the vendor can
start performing the work.
Now they can start performing the work for
us.
And so now we're going to monitor and
control the work that they're doing.
And that's what control procurement refers
to.
It's trying to quantify the ability,
or rather we are trying to quantify the
ability for the seller to actually perform
the work.
How well are they performing?
Control procurement
refers to identifying the
success and failures of the
procurement relationship?
Are they doing the work that they're
supposed to be doing?
Right.
And how efficiently are they performing?
One of the key things to
remember in procurement
is that now we are the customer, right?
We are the customer.
The vendor is performing the work for us.
So we are going to give our requirements
to the vendor.
So we are the key stakeholders.
We are the ones that are signing off on
the work for the vendor.
That's one very important factor to
understand when it comes to procurement.
Because we are the customer now,
everything that we've been talking about
up until now has been
from the point of view of us
being the project team
working for the customer.
But this time now, it's the other way
around.
We are the customer and the vendor is
working for us.
Okay.